Have you ever bought Ethereum? Do you
like Ethereum? Do you like altcoins?
Because Ethereum has just done something
for the first time in six years. And it
could be a huge clue for what is going
to happen next for altcoins, your
favorite altcoin. I want to share with
you this chart right here. And for the
first time in 6 years, Ethereum has
broken this trend line. [music] And in
this video, I'm going to explain what I
think is about to happen to Ethereum and
all of your favorite altcoins. Let's get
into it. Recently, many of you have been
randomly unsubscribed from [music] my
channel. And missing just one video in a
market like this can cost you big time.
So, stop what you're doing, look down,
and make sure you are subscribed. So,
here we are. We are in Ethereum US
dollar 4month Coinbase chart and we have
this trend line in white. This trend
line in white connects the candles from
January 2020 as support followed by the
May 2020 as support followed by touch
points in May 2022 with this huge wick
down to this trend line and another
support zone of September 2022.
Now what you'll notice in this chart is
that we started this trend line back in
2020. We rallied significantly
all the way up to almost $5,000
only to plummet all the way back down
from where we started from. Having huge
wicks showing the bottom of this market
back in 2022 only to absolutely
skyrocket once again to around the same
price only to crash back down to where
we are today. But it's not just that. We
actually rallied up to a double top. And
what you'll notice in a lot of altcoin
charts is they did something similar
where the rally of our past market cycle
top in your favorite altcoins could be
around the prior market cycle top of
another previous rally. In other words,
we just had a double top. Not only did
we have a double top in Ethereum, we had
a double top, which by the way is a
trend reversal. Anytime you have one top
and then years later, another top happen
around the same price points. You can
see these wicks here are a whole bunch
of profit taking. These wicks here, a
whole bunch of profit taking. In other
words, when you see wicks on the upside,
it means you have pressure downward
because that momentum of selling is like
a rock tumbling down a mountain. It just
collects steam. And that's what you saw
in that 5,000ish price range. In other
words, the double top pushed us down so
much that we just broke this trend line
for the first time in six years. This is
not good in any way, shape or form. And
it means something very particular to
Ethereum and the rest of the altcoin
market will be affected. Ethereum leads
the charge for altcoins and whatever
Ethereum does will send shock waves and
it'll be this chain reaction to the rest
of the altcoin market. Take a look more
closely. So as we started that journey
in 2022 with the bottom of that market
creating this trend line having an
absolute domination in price rallying
into that 5,000 area. What we did before
then is we rallied up until roughly
4,000 and from 4,000 we came back down
to that trend line. We needed to confirm
support from that trend line and we
weren't ready to get into the 5,000
area. Notice how these are channels.
These are what I like to call channels.
You see this yellow line that we have on
our chart? That's that top channel.
That's where we saw our double top. The
channel between then is where we went
from our bottom. We rallied into this
area. We realized Ethereum did not have
enough momentum to get into the 5,000
area. We realized we needed to take a
breath. We realized we needed a
pullback. And luckily for Ethereum, it
held support at exactly that same area
that it did years earlier. And back here
in January 2025, that's when things got
very interesting. We had a long wick to
the lower side, which means one thing
and one thing only. We have buying
pressure coming in. We have momentum to
the upside. And that protection of this
trend line led us into that $5,000 area
only to be met with that double top and
only to be absolutely plummet back down
to this support zone. And this was
Ethereum's biggest test of years and
years and years was the candle from at
the beginning of this year, the first
four months of this year to be exact.
And what you can see is an absolute
protection. We were trying like hell to
protect this area and we wanted to have
a rebound the other way. We did so much
as to create this huge lower wick which
told us that there was a lot of buying
in that area. We were trying to protect.
I have to say for the record, Ethereum
is one of my favorite altcoins. I love
the crypto markets. I've been studying
the crypto markets and covering the
crypto markets for almost 10 years here
on YouTube. And what you see happening
before your eyes, it's sad for Ethereum.
It has held this trend line for six
years. It tried like hell and we are in
the candle that could break the camel's
back right now and especially the next
candle after that will tell us
everything that we need to know and it
happens right with this trend line.
Okay, so right now we're in this limbo
area of how is this thing going to
close? What's going to happen? But we do
know that there are channels. Okay,
there's a channel from roughly 2,200
to roughly 1,400. That's a very specific
channel. And the channel below that goes
from 1,400
and it stops around here roughly at 870.
Okay, that's that bottom channel here
where you pick up some of this area from
2017 Ethereum where this was our
resistance and eventually our support in
2022. That's where it leaves the altcoin
market. What you'll notice is I want you
to take a look at some of the OG
altcoins and some of the OG altcoins.
You're going to notice a reoccurring
pattern of double tops or something very
very similar to that. And what you'll
notice is that we may be in this period
of change for altcoins. Old coins saw
their glory days, especially in 2017,
and since then it's been a bit of a
struggle. And I think this is breaking
the camel's back. I think this is the
point at which altcoins take a reset.
They start to shift and a lot of the
altcoins are going to find their true
identity with this. Do I think Ethereum
is dead? No. Do I think Ethereum is
going to struggle a little bit? Yes. Do
I think altcoins will also struggle a
little bit? Especially if you watch this
video in 2028, you're probably asking
yourself, where's that altcoin rally?
Why isn't it as big? When are they going
to explode? And everyone will tell you
to wait until 2029. Then 2029 comes in
2029 ends and you're like, "Wait a
minute. We didn't have an altcoin rally
yet. We didn't where's the altcoin
season? We didn't have one." I think
that's going to be what's taking form in
2029 into 2030. And by 2020, 2030,
everybody's going to sit there and say,
"You know what? Why in hell there wasn't
there an altcoin rally? It's got to be
coming. Like it's got to it's going to
come this year." No, the market's going
to start going down in 2030. And reality
will set in in 2031. When you're sitting
there, if you're watching this video in
2031, you're like, "Damn, maybe Steve
was on to something. Maybe altcoins will
never be the same again." But they will
go through a period. They will regain
their their power just like Bitcoin and
it will come again. But more on those
videos later. I just wanted to let you
know based on facts that all coins just
changed and they may have changed
forever. Trade like a tourist or go with
the pros. The FFA is where the real ones
go.